<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Odilia Screen Reader</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Odilia Screen Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 23:12:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://odilia.app/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Odilia Version 0.1.0 Released</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/release_0-1-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 22:30:18 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/news/release_0-1-0/</guid><description>After many months&amp;mdash;just over a year of hard work, we are proud to announce the initial, beta release of Odilia: a new, fast, lightweight, screenreader for Linux. Thanks to all the others who have been instrumental in making Odilia possible:
@albertotirla (BGTLover) @mcb2003 (Fake VIP) @luukvanderduim (Luuk Van Der Duim) @samtay (Sam Tay) Federico Mena and Emmanuel Bassi at GNOME for answering my questions. @lparcq (Laurent Pelecq) on Gitlab for the creation of a speech library.</description></item><item><title>One More Thing - Final Prototype Released</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/one-more-prototype/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/news/one-more-prototype/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we &lt;a href="../enough-prototypes">announced recently&lt;/a>, we decided that we&amp;rsquo;d learned enough from &lt;a href="https://github.com/odilia-app/odilia-prototype">the Odilia prototype&lt;/a>
to actually implement the real thing. The prototype code, while functional, prioritised experimentation over quality,
and thus we&amp;rsquo;ll be throwing almost all of it out completely, but the code is far less important than the experience we
gained from writing it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enough Prototypes, let's do this for real</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/enough-prototypes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 12:06:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/news/enough-prototypes/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of afew days ago, we decided we played enough with the tools and components of the linux accessibility stack to be
able to say that we aren&amp;rsquo;t so ignorant anymore, we know at least the basics about how it all fits together, how our
screenreaders read information from a linux gui app, how the gui toolkit and atspi work together to provide the required
context for such tools to operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bore you with code snippets, git logs, conversations from who knows how much time ago and so on, I
will quickly give you a rundown of everything we learned during this long, laborious but nevertheless fun and
educational journey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First Prototype Has been Released!</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/first-prototype/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 22:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/news/first-prototype/</guid><description>We know it has been a long time, however we are delighted to inform you that the first Odilia prototype is up on GitHub, with a very early alpha stage build for anyone curious enough to try it out.
If you want to try it out, the link is here:
https://github.com/yggdrasil-sr/yggdrasil-prototype/releases/
the screen reader can&amp;rsquo;t do much at the moment, however this is what it can do so far
like any normal screen reader, it can read most components exposed by the Linux accessibility interface, such as buttons, checkboxes, radio buttons, etc.</description></item><item><title>Minimal speech-dispatcher Bindings Created</title><link>https://odilia.app/news/minimal-speech-dispatcher-bindings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 15:24:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/news/minimal-speech-dispatcher-bindings/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of afew days ago, a &lt;a href="https://github.com/odilia-app/tts_subsystem">minimal binding to speech-dispatcher&lt;/a> (the TTS system for Linux) was created, which
wraps the C functions provided by &lt;a href="https://github.com/ndarilek/speech-dispatcher-sys">Nolan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>speech-dispatcher-sys&lt;/code> crate&lt;/a> in a safe Rust API.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>