<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Documentation on Odilia Screen Reader</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/user/</link><description>Recent content in User Documentation on Odilia Screen Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:27:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://odilia.app/doc/user/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Odilia</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/user/installation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 14:03:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/doc/user/installation/</guid><description>Requirements Odilia should run on any Unix-like platform with the required dependencies supported by Rust . Currently, we primarily target Linux, however, we plan to support other free operating systems such as *BSD in the future (patches welcome).
The following dependencies are required to build and run Odilia:
Build Dependencies Rust Runtime Dependenceis speech-dispatcher &amp;gt;= 0.9 - text to speech daemon at-spi2-core - accessibility infrastructure Odilia doesn&amp;rsquo;t use libatspi, it interacts with AT-SPI over DBus directly, but the daemon must be running.</description></item><item><title>Odilia Users Guide</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/user/guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:27:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/doc/user/guide/</guid><description>Odilia should start speaking immediately when started.
Some things may feel different.
What Works Caret navigation. Tab navigation. aria-live regions on a web page will speak in real time. What Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Work Terminals &amp;ndash; Odilia will read the entire buffer, not just the new lines. Key bindings Structural navigation</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/user/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/doc/user/faq/</guid><description>Why don&amp;rsquo;t you support keybindings? Currently, key bindings are very hard to register across arbitrary desktop environments. We will be working on this for the next release.
How do I change my speech rate? Your speech rate must be changed in your speech dispatcher settings. This is often in a file called speechd.conf either in your $XDG_HOME directory, or in /etc/speech-dispatcher/. The value you want to change is DefaultRate. It accepts a value between 0 and 100.</description></item></channel></rss>