<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developer Documentation on Odilia Screen Reader</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/devel/</link><description>Recent content in Developer Documentation on Odilia Screen Reader</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:27:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://odilia.app/doc/devel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/devel/design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 13:53:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/doc/devel/design/</guid><description>Components Screen readers are complex applications that need to interact with many different systems and technologies, and Odilia is no different. For this reason, the project is split into several crates:
Odilia &amp;ndash; The main application This is the toplevel binary crate, which glues all the smaller crates together. It also handles logging and other application-wide tasks.
atspi &amp;ndash; Accessibility Interface This crate communicates with the Assistive Technology Service Provider Interface, which allows Odilia to access and present the content in applications and the desktop environment.</description></item><item><title>Useful Links</title><link>https://odilia.app/doc/devel/useful-links/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 15:07:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://odilia.app/doc/devel/useful-links/</guid><description>AT-SPI General overview, with several links Accessible Document Navigation Using AT-SPI API documentation Examples, including Javascript, C and Python Examples exclusively using py-atspi2, the human-generated bindings, not the ones generated via GObject Introspection Odilia&amp;rsquo;s atspi crate Speech libspeech library documentation Speech Synthesis Interface Protocol (SSIP) API documentation Speech Synthesis Markup Language (SSML) Version 1.1 Raw FFI Rust bindings to libspeech Idiomatic Rust bindings to libspeech, what we&amp;rsquo;re currently using Pure Rust interface to speech-dispatcher, what we&amp;rsquo;d like to use Odilia&amp;rsquo;s tts crate Braille Liblouis users and programmers manual Liblouis bindings for rust, for braille tables and multiple braille codes, including those for the majority of languages Libbrlapi reference manual</description></item></channel></rss>